[Music]
fudgy
dinosaurs galore got all dug up till
there were no more
a flavor redesign might be doable but
fossil fuel
is non-renewable that's what ben and
jerry said
or say on their website about this
flavour fossil fuel
i mean you can understand why they took
it off the shelf the name
alone that's it it's nothing to do with
the flavor i think it was really really
popular it was over here anyway
but obviously the name fossil fuel it's
frowned upon
now i agree that we should stop using
fossil fuels as soon as possible
but it's just an ice cream flavor so
we're going to try and recreate it now
it's quite an easy one to make but to
make it accurate you do need a dinosaur
silicone mold thankfully we have one
this ice cream was only available from
2005 to 2010 so it's
been off the shelf for years so uh time
to bring it back
the actual flavor is according to ben
and joe's website is a sweet cream
ice cream with chocolate cookie pieces
fudge dinos and a fudge swell
all sounds pretty good time to resurrect
no
excavate
[Music]
so the base for this is really simple
the original version is just a sweet
cream base so no flavor at all
but we're going to add a little bit of
vanilla in this just to make it a little
bit more interesting
so put all your ingredients in a pan and
heat it up nice and gently
then add your vanilla essence or extract
that's totally up to you
now as a stabilizer we've decided to use
something called silk gel
which is a mono and diglycerides of
fatty acids just in case you were
not aware once your ice cream base is up
to temperature
and your silk gel is dissipated properly
take it off the heat put it in container
and chill it down for a minimum four
hours
[Music]
the next thing we're going to do is make
the little dinosaur shapes now for this
we're just going to use
plain old milk chocolate nothing else so
we're going to use
the belgian chocolate the milk callouts
that we have here
wear out however much you need we're
going to use 60 grams in this one
melt it in the microwave just keep an
eye on it and then pour it into your
mould
make sure all the little holes filled up
and then pop it in the freezer
after about an hour remove your mould
from the freezer take your chocolate
shapes out and put them in a container
pop them back in the freezer until
you're ready to use them
the final make here is for the fudge
swirl
we're going to use the fudge well we
used in our last video which i
absolutely adore
take your chocolate and butter and melt
it in the microwave whilst that's
melting
put your sugar and egg in another bowl
and give it a good whisk
then take your melted chocolate butter
out the microwave and combine the two
and whisk it well to combine pop it in
another container
and then you're ready to pour it in as
you batch your ice cream
and the last element of fossil fuel is
the cookies
i'm rubbish at making cookies so i've
just bought some chewy ones from our
local supermarket and we're going to
tear those up and put them in the ice
cream
but if you're actually good at making
cookies unlike me feel free to use your
favorite recipe for this
once your base is chilled down take it
out and pop it in your ice cream machine
this machine here is the muzo stella so
the 50 30
and this will turn this entire recipe in
12 minutes
yours most likely will take longer if
you're not using this machine
[Music]
when your ice cream is churned take it
out and start loading up your tub
all you've got to do here is put your
cookies your fudge
and your chocolate shapes in however you
want make sure you give it a little bit
of a stir to mix them all in well
pop it in the freezer for a few hours
until you're ready to eat it
the ice cream has been in the freezer
overnight let's get it straight out now
get some dished up see what it looks
like
[Music]
another great tub and if you see that
there i mean look
prontos or i don't know what they are
i'm not you know an expert on dinos but
look at them
great first thing i want to touch on is
the silk gel
this is the first time i've used this
stuff i mean it's a great company you
get loads of different stabilizers and
emulsifiers and whatever you need for
baking cooking ice cream
all companies it as a whole
it the the modern diglycerides of fatty
acids
is a very well known stabilizer in ice
cream
but i've never used them in this kind of
form before does it work
let's find out it does
is it worth the extra money no just
stick with milk powder the actual result
is
incredibly similar i mean i probably
in my personal opinion milk powder does
a better job
maybe it's just me maybe i haven't used
it right if you've used this mono and
diglycerides of fatty acids
i don't know how many times i can say
that successfully if you've used it
let us know in the comments let me know
what you think see if you'd uh use it
again or whether you'd stick with
locust being gum or whatever else you
use
the fudge core it's not fudge core at
all it's fudge swirl
the fudge will all look there's bits of
chocolate and everything in there
and cookie that's a really good combo
the fudge well
the cookie the bits of milk chocolate
very very slight bit of vanilla flavor
to the ice cream
it's a really good ice cream it's a
really good flavor
ben and jerry's bring this back
change your name if you like it's fine
call it whatever you like but it is a
really really good flavor
i hope you've enjoyed this video on
fossil fuel and come back to the next
one we've actually reached our 150
subscriber mark already so yay
we're gonna start editing
our next big video it's a big marvel
video
and it's taking me ages so sorry if it
takes me a couple more weeks to get it
out but
bear with me it will be worth the wait
hope you like and subscribe thanks very
much for watching see you next time
[Music]
excavate corny
you